NAME: Dr Victor Moinina

HOME ADDRESS: 6j Off Johnson Street, Aberdeen, Freetown TELEPHONE: +23280139982, +23278484553, +23231917664 E-MAIL: moninavicky@hotmail.co.uk; moninavicky@gmail.com;

SKYPE: victor.edmond.moinina

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/victor-moinina-81234a7a/

NATIONALITY: Sierra Leonean DATE OF BIRTH: 5th July 1989 MARITAL STATUS: Engaged

S.E.X.: Male

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a young, dynamic, adaptive, and skilful person, which warrants my switch between academic and job circles; quick to learn, a self-starter, competent at decision-making and implementation and an excellent motivator to others. With accumulated educational and work experiences, I am well-grounded in critical analysis, independent and teamwork. As a positive thinker, I possess a deep conviction for moral and ethical values.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- o Translator- L.Q.A.- Krio to English, English to Krio, January 2021- Present
- o Board Chair- Advocate for the Rights of Women and Girls Sierra Leone, September 2021- Present
- o Lecturer 1- Institute of Public Administration and Management, University of Sierra Leone, Freetown, Sierra Leone, April 2021- Present
- Executive Director/ Lead Consultant- Pro-Idealist Limited, Freetown, Sierra Leone, January 2021- Present
- Policy and Research Lead- Volunteering Involving Organisations Network (VIONet)
 Sierra Leone- October 2020- Present
- o Programme Policy Officer- A.U. Youth Volunteer World Food Programme Ethiopia, Jijiga, Somali Region, Ethiopia, October 2019- October 2020
- O National Early Warning Systems Manager/Head of Programs/ Deputy National Network Coordinator- West Africa Network of Peacebuilding-Sierra Leone (WANEP-SL), Freetown, Sierra Leone, May 2016-September 2017
- Secretary- Placement and Internship- Federation of Young Economists in West Africa, Bamako, Mali, May 2016- Present
- o Program Officer- E.C.O.W.A.S. Youth Council, Abuja, Nigeria, November 2016-January 2017
- o Intern, Campaign for Good Governance, Freetown, Sierra Leone, May-August 2016
- C.E.O. and Founder, Forum for the Development of Young People in Sierra Leone, August 2011-December 2016

- o Chapter head, Africa 2.0 Sierra Leone, April 2014- April 2015
- O Student Engagement Leader, Mamaye Campaign with Evidence for action international and Forum for the Development of Young People in Sierra Leone, February 2014- May 2014
- Volunteer Teacher, St. Joseph's Secondary School, Sierra Leone, May 2013- September
 2014
- Marketing Officer, Besworth Micro-Finance Company, Ghana, January 2013- March
 2013
- National Coordinator, Forum for the Empowerment of Women and Girls, Sierra Leone,
 July 2010- July 2011
- Assistant National Coordinator, One Young World Sierra Leone, Sierra Leone, June 2009- June 2010
- o Enumerator- Graceland Counseling Centre, Kol at tok, Sierra Leone, December 2009
- Enumerator- National Public Procurement Authority Price Survey, Sierra Leone, May
 2009
- o Public Relations Officer- We are the World Charity organization, July 2008- June 2010

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

- o Delegate- PhD Program, P.A.U.G.H.S.S.; Cameroon- October 2017-December 2020
- o Associate Consultant- Kalube Consults, Uganda: April 2017-Date
- o Consultant, Big Bang Company; October 2017-Date
- o Consultant, Inspiration Lifeline; February 2019- Date
- Focal Person- Volunteer Involving Organisations Network (Vionet), June 2016- December 2016
- Sierra Leone Representative at the Pan University of Governance and Social Sciences,
 Second Batch, November 2014- January 2017
- Associate Director, International Youth Action Against Terrorism (I.Y.A.A.T.), Kenya; May-December 2015
- o Global Youth Ambassador for Sierra Leone, A World at School and U.N. Education Foundation, August 2014- Date
- Youth for Change ambassador for Sierra Leone, Department for International Development and U.K. Aid, August 2014- August 2015
- o 11th and 12th Tunza Ecogeneration Ambassador to Sierra Leone, United Nations Environment Program and Samsung Engineering, September 2013- September 2014
- o Founding Member- Africa Youth Commission, November 2013- Date
- Team Lead / Coordinator Western Area Urban- National Elections Watch (NEW): June-December 2012

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

o 2017- 2020: P.A.U.G.H.S.S., University of Yaoundé II, PhD in Governance and Regional Integration, Completed with a Distinction



- o 2015-2017: P.A.U.G.H.S.S., University of Yaoundé II, MSc in Governance and Regional Integration, 2.1 equivalent
- 2008-2013: Fourah Bay College, University of Sierra Leone, Bachelor of Arts, 2nd Division Upper
- 2006-2008: St. Edwards Secondary School, Sierra Leone, West African Senior Secondary Certificate Examinations
- o 2004-2006: The International School Limited-Secondary, London G.C.E. Ordinary Levels
- o 2001 2004 -The International School Limited- Secondary, Sierra Leone, Basic Education Certificate Examinations
- 1995-2001 -Becklyn Nursery and Preparatory School, Sierra Leone, National Primary School Examinations

CONSULTANCIES DONE

- o SEND Sierra Leone 2018-2019
- Restless Development/ UNICEF 2021
- o A.F.T.E.C. 2020 to 2021
- o DsTI 2022 to 2023

LANGUAGES

o English (Excellent), French (Average), Krio-Mother tongue (Excellent), Pidgin English (Very Good).

SKILLS

- o Organizational management, Social Science/Development Research, Community Development, Volunteerism, Leadership, Youth Development, Project design, writing, implementation and Management, Mentoring, public speaking, Teaching, Sensitization, Mediation and Computing (mastery of M.S. Word, MS Publisher, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint), and Internet surfing
- o Topaz Simulation training

CERTIFICATES COURSES

- ➤ WTO Trade facilitation agreement and regional trade facilitation rules and regulations-U.N.I.T.A.R.- November 2016
- ➤ Women, Business and the Law 2020 (Unpaid Consultancy)- World Bank Group- January 2020
- ➤ Minerals Resources Policy and Contract Negotiations- The African Institute for Economic Development and Planning (I.D.E.P.)- May 2020

REFERENCES:



- Dr Isata Mahoi, Minister of Gender and Children's Affairs, Former National Network Coordinator, West Africa Network for Peacebuilding- Sierra Leone, isatamahoi.unimak@gmail.com, +232 76 586853 (Former Supervisor)
- Moses O.J.O.T.A., Head of Programmes, World Food Programme- Somali Region, Ethiopia, moses.ojota@wfp.org, +251 90 257 7169 (Former Supervisor)
- Samuel Byrne, Director, Inspiration Lifeline Consultancy- Sierra Leone,
 jbyrne_bo@yahoo.com, +232 76 870202 (Mentor)